const questions=
[
  // 6th Grade
  [
    //english
    [
      {
        "question": "Complete this sentence: 'I am happy to report that Grace’s baby is very___and ___!'",
        "options":["A. happy and healthy","B. sickly and scrawny","C. tiny and small","D. hungry and annoying"],
        "answer":"A. happy and healthy"
      },
      {
        "question":"Complete this sentence: 'The riverbed was ___ and ___, making it hard to balance.'",
        "options": ["A. fishy and froggy","B. shallow and deep","C. moist and wet","D. rocky and slippery"],
        "answer":"D. rocky and slippery"
      },
      {
        "question":"Complete this sentence: 'She was brave __ a lion.'",
        "options": ["A. as","B. because","C. before","D. so"],
        "answer":"A. as"
      },
      // {
      //   "question":"The car belonging to the manager,Choose the correct answer for the following phrase",
      //   "options":["A. The managers car","B. The manager's car","C. The managers'car","D. The managerss's car"],
      //   "answer":"B. The manager's car"

      // },
    {
      "question":"What is the pronoun in this sentence? 'James took the book; he gave it to the teacher.'",
      "options":["A. book","B. he","C. James","D. teacher"],
      "answer":"B. he"

    },
    // {
    //   "question":"Their business's success was far greater than what even they themselves had dared to imagine",
    //   "options":["A.  Reflexive","B. Intensive"],
    //   "answer":"B. Intensive"
    // },
    {
      "question":"The root 'therm' means heat. What does the word thermostat mean?",
      "options":["A.  A device that controls the lighting a room",
                "B.  A device that controls the music a room",
                "C.  A device that controls the airflow in a room",
                "D.  A device that controls the heating in a room"],                                        
      "answer":"D.  A device that controls the heating in a room."
    },
    {
      "question":" What is a homonym?", 
      "options":["A. A word that imitate sounds or ideas",
                "B. Words that are spelled the same but have different definitions",
                "C. Words that describe, identify or further define a noun or a pronoun",
                "D. Word that shows possession"],                                        
      "answer":   "B. Words that are spelled the same but have different definitions."
    },
    {
      "question":"What is a metaphor?",
      "options":["A. words that replaces one or more nouns",
                "B. words that follows a conjunction",
                "C. words that shows possession",
                "D. words used that represent something else"],                                        
      "answer": "D. words used that represent something else"
      },
      {

        "question":"'That meal should stick to his ribs for a while!' This means:",
        "options":["A. to feel hungry",
        "B. to last",
        "C. to cause him indigestion",
        "D. to remain in his stomach"],
        "answer":"B. to last"
      }
    ],

         //6th grade Math

    [
      {
      "question":"7 + -3 = ?",
        "options":["A. -4","B. 10","C. 4","D. -10"],
      "answer":"C. 4"
      },
      {
        "question":"5 divided by 5 x 3 = ?",
        "options":["A. 3","B. 15","C. 1","D. 4"],
        "answer":"A. 3"
      },
      {
      "question":"3 x 2 + 4 = ?",
      "options":["A. 10","B. 11","C. 5","D. 7"],
      "answer":"A. 10"
      },
      {
        "question":"4 + -3 = ?",
        "options":["A. 2","B. 1","C. -2","D. 0"],
        "answer":"B. 1"

      },
      {
        "question":"92,982 – 91,900 = ?",
        "options":["A. 1033","B. 1082","C. 1043","D. 1039"],
        "answer":"B. 1082"

      },
      {
        "question":"The answer to -10 × 1 is: ",
        "options":["A. positive","B. negative"],
        "answer":"B. negative"
      },
      {
        "question":"Are the ratios '10:14' and '5:7' equivalent?",
        "options":["A. Yes","B. No"],
        "answer":"A. Yes"
      },
      {
        "question":"Select the ratio equivalent to 7:6:",
        "options":["A. 63:54","B. 21:19","C. 43:36","D. 77:65"],
        "answer":"A. 63:54"
      },
      {
        "question":"Mark can make 42 birthday cakes in 7 days. How many can he make in 3 days?",
        "options":["A. 20 cakes","B. 21 cakes","C. 22 cakes","D. 18 cakes"],
        "answer":"D. 18"
      },
      {
        "question":"An estimated 3 out of every 25 people are left-handed. What percentage is this?",
        "options":["A. 18 percent","B. 50 percent","C. 12 percent","D. 6 percent"],
        "answer":"C. 12 percent"
      }
    ],

          //   6th grade Science
   

    [
      {
        "question":"I have dry scaly skin, breathe with lungs, and lay shelled eggs. What am I?",
        "options":["A. A primate","B. A reptile","C. An amphibian","D. A cephalopod"],
        "answer":"B. A reptile"
      },
      {
        "question":"A blood cell:",
        "options":["A. Carries messages throughout the body",
                  "B. Controls the size of the cell openings",
                  "C. Carries oxygen throughout the body",
                  "D. Controls the flow of blood"],
        "answer":"C. Carries oxygen throughout the body"
      },
      //   {
      //   "question":"What is the density of an iron block that has a volume of 61 cubic cm and a mass of 122 grams?", 
      //   "options":["A. 14","B. 4","C. 44","D. 2"],
      //   "answer":"D. 2"
      // },
      {
        "question":"What does 'K' stand for in the Table of Elements?",
        "options":["A. Krypton","B. Holmium","C. Xenon","D. Potassium"],
        "answer":"D. Potassium"

      },
      {
        "question":"What does SN stand for in the Table of Elements?",
        "options":["A. Tennessine","B. Tin","C. Sulfur","D. Gold"],
        "answer":"B. Tin"

      },
      {
        "question":"Which of these elements has a density of 1.7?",
        "options":["A. Fluorine","B. Calcium","C. Carbon","D.Chlorine"],
        "answer":"A. Fluorine"
      },
      {
        "question":"Which of these elements has the atomic number of 15?",
        "options":["A. Phosphorus","B. Sodium","C. Holmium","D. Argon"],
        "answer":"A. Phosphorus"
      },
      {
        "question":"In what year was Neon discovered as an element?",
        "options":["A. 1877","B. 1887","C. 1898","D. 1889"],
        "answer":"C. 1898"
      },
      {
        "question":"Which of these elements makes up 18% of the human body?",
        "options":["A. Oxygen","B. Carbon","C. Hydrogen","D. Sodium"],
        "answer":"B. Carbon"
      },
      {
        "question":"Earth is comprised of which two types of crust:",
        "options":["A. Continental crust and Canopy crust",
                  "B. Underbody crust and Oceanic crust",
                  "C. Continental crust and Oceanic crust",
                  "D. Mantle crust and Underbody crust"],
                  "answer":"C. Continental crust and Oceanic crust"
      }
      ],
  
  // Grade 6 history 
  
    [
      {
        "question":"Who was the fourth President of the United States?",
        "options":["A. John Adams","B. Thomas Jefferson","C. Alexander Hamilton","D. James Madison"],
        "answer":"D. James Madison"
      },
      {
        "question":" Which of these offices is part of the Judicial Branch?",
        "options":["A. the Department of Defense","B. Congress","C. the President","D. Supreme Court"],
        "answer":"D. Supreme Court"
      },
      {
        "question":"The First Amendment protects citizens': ",
        "options":["A. voting rights, right to own weapons",
                    "B. freedom of speech, freedom of religion",
                    "C. freedom to own private property"],
        "answer":"B. freedom of speech, freedom of religion"
      },
      {
        "question":" Which of these states was NOT a member of the original 13 colonies?",
        "options":["A. Maine","B. Pennsylvania",
                    "C. Delaware","D. Georgia"],
        "answer":"A. Maine"
      },
      {
        "question": "Susan B. Anthony is famous for:",
        "options": ["A. Acting as the first First Lady of the U.S.", "B. Leading the women's suffrage movement", "C. Inventing the polling station.", "D. Being the first woman to vote"],
        "answer": "B. Leading the women's suffrage movement"
      },
      {
        "question":"Who is famous for the quote— 'Give me liberty or give me death!'",
        "options":["A. Patrick Henry","B. Samuel Adams",
                    "C. Thomas Paine","D. George Washington"],
        "answer":"A. Patrick Henry" 
      },
      {
        "question":"The Civil Rights Movement refers to: ",
        "options": ["A. The fight for rights for women", "B. The fight for 2nd Amendment rights", "C. The activism to secure full human rights for African Americans from 1946-1968"],
        "answer":"C. The activism to secure full human rights for African Americans from 1946-1968"
      },
      // {
      //   "question":"In what battle did George Washingtoncending the Revolutionary War?",
      //   "options":["A. Lexington and Concord,1776",
      //                 "B. the Siege of Yorktown,1781",
      //                 "C. Battle at Bunker Hill,1775",
      //                 "D. Battle at Chesapeake,1781"],
      //   "answer":"B. the Siege of Yorktown,1781"
      // },
      {
        "question":"Which city was the first Capitol of the United States?",
        "options":["A. New York, NY","B. Philadelphia, PA","C. Trenton,NJ","D. Washington DC"],
        "answer":"A. New York, NY"
      },
      {
      "question":"How many stars were on the original United States flag?",
      "options":["A. 5","B. 13",
                  "C. 4","D. 12"],
      "answer":"B. 13"
      }
    ]
  ],

   // 7th Grade 
  [
    //7th Grade English
    [
      {
        "question":"What kind of statement is this? — 'The audience's thunderous applause left me completely speechless!'",
        "options":["A. Declarative","B. Iterrogative","C. Exclamatory","D. Question"],
        "answer":"C. Exclamatory"
      },
      // {
      //   "question":"Mrs. Shen gave Marshall the solo because he sang it the ___ of everyone who auditioned.",
      //   "options":["A. worse","B. best","C. well","D. better"],
      //   "answer":"B. best"
      // },
      { 
        "question":"Alphabetically, which word comes first: upstairs, upon, upward, upper",
        "options":["A.Upper","B. Upstairs","C. Upon","D. upward"],
        "answer":"C. Upon"
      },
      {
        "question":"Which group pre-dates the other?",
        "options":["A. Dinosaurs","B. Humans","C. Both","D. Neither"],
        "answer":"A. Dinosaurs"
      },
      { 
        "question":"When does a basketball team complete its pregame warm-up?",
        "options":["A. During half-time",
                   "B. Before the 2nd quarter",
                   "C. Right before the game begins",
                   "D. Before the fourth quarter"],
        "answer":"C. Right before the game begins"
      },
      // {
      //   "question":"The kayak trainer gave __ and the other couples life jackets and matching helmets?",
      //   "options":["A. us","B. we","C. them","D. they"], 
      //   "answer":"A. us"
      // },
      { 
        "question":"The actress gave my best friend and __ her autograph?",
        "options":["A. we","B. I","C. me","D. she"],
        "answer":"B. I"
      },
      // {
      //   "question":"Which of these is a complete sentence?",
      //   "options":["A. Butter melts in a skillet",
      //             "B. Sugar and salt dissove in water",
      //             "C. The train was late.",
      //             "D. Mrs. Spencer is giving away several of her old coats to the charity drive"],
      //   "answer":"D. Mrs.Spencer is giving away several of her old coats to the charity drive"
      // },
      {
        "question":"Which word is an antonym of 'fictitious?'",
        "options":["A. Delightful",
        "B. Beautiful",
        "C. Imaginary",
        "D. Real"],
        "answer":"D. Real"
      },
      {
        "question":"Which word is a synonym of 'maternal?'",
        "options":["A. Mature",
        "B. Motherly",
        "C. Fatherly",
        "D. Materialistic"],
        "answer": "B. Motherly"
      }  
  ],

  // 7th Grade Math
  
  [
    {
      "question":"John eats 3/5th of a candy bar. What percentage of the candy bar is this?",
      "options":["A. 80%","B. 6%","C. 35%","D. 60%"],
      "answer":"D. 60%"
    },
    // {
    //   "question":"What representes (-4)",
    //   "options":["A. (+) (-) (+) (+) (+) (+)",
    //   "B. (-) (-) (+) (+)",
    //   "C. (+) (-) (+) (-) (-) (-) (-) (-)",
    //   "D. (-) (+) (-) (-) (-)"],
    //   "answer":"C. (+) (-) (+) (-) (-) (-) (-) (-)"
    // },
    {
      "question":"Calculate: (-8) + (+2) - (-6) = ?",
      "options":["A. -12","B. 0","C. 4","D. 16"],
      "answer":"B. 0"
    },
    {
      "question":"What is the greatest common factor of 12 and 16?",
      "options":["A. 6","B. 3","C. 2","D. 4"],
      "answer":"D. 4"
    },
    {
      "question":"Is -9 minus 6 positive or negative?",
      "options":["A. Positive",
      "B. Negative"],
      "answer":"B. Negative"
    },
    {
      "question":"Is 9 plus -8 positive or negative?",
      "options":["A. Positive",
      "B. Negative"],
      "answer":"A. Positive"
    },
    {
      "question":"Is -82 plus -83 positive or negative?",
      "options":["A. Positive",
      "B. Negative"],
      "answer":"B. Negative"
    },
    {
      "question":"What number multiplied by itself will give you 625?",
      "options":["A. 17","B. 62","C. 25","D. 15"],
      "answer":"C. 25"
    },
    {
      "question":"What is the cube root of -343?",
      "options":["A. 12","B. 7","C. 9","D. -7"],
      "answer":"D. -7"
    },
    {
      "question":"What is the cube root of 216?",
      "options":["A. 8","B. 4","C. -6","D. 6"],
      "answer":"D. 6"
    }
  ], 
 

  // 7th Grade Science
  [
    {
      "question":"Estimate the approximate temperature of a warm grilled cheese sandwich:",
      "options":["A. 20 degrees F",
                 "B. 55 degress C",
                 "C. 55 degress F",
                 "D. 90 degrees C"],
      "answer": "B. 55 degress C"
    },
    {
    "question":"Estimate the approximate temperature of a cool glass of milk:",
    "options":["A. 3 degrees C",
               "B. 55 degress C",
               "C. 2 degress  F",
               "D. 45 degrees F"],
    "answer":"D. 45 degrees F"
    },
    {
      "question":"What is the 'brain' (command center) of a cell?",
      "options":["A. Mitochondria","B. Nucleus","C. Cytoplasm","D. Ribosomes)"],
      "answer":"B. Nucleus"
    },
    {
      "question":" The ____ membrane allows materials to enter and leave the cell.",
      "options":["A. Plasma","B. Golgi Body","C. Cytoplasm","D. Ribosomes"],
      "answer":"A. Plasma"
    },
    {
      "question":"What are the three main parts of a cell?",
      "options":[ "A. Cell membrane, mitochondria, cytoplasm",
                  "B. Cell membrane, nucleus, cytoplasm",
                  "C. Nucleus, vacuole, golgi body",
                  "D. Golgi Body, endoplasmic reticulum, lysosomes"],
      "answer":"B. Cell membrane, nucleus, cytoplasm"
    },
    {
      "question":"Where is the energy of a cell created?",
      "options":["A. Cell membrane",
                 "B. Cytoplasm",
                 "C. Vacuole",
                 "D. Mitochondria"],
      "answer":"D. Mitochondria"
    },
    {
      "question":"What is the responsibility of Chloroplasts?",
      "options":[ "A. Protect the cell",
                  "B. Keep the structure of the cell",
                  "C. Control workings of the cell",
                  "D. Make energy from sunlight"],
      "answer": "D. Make energy from sunlight"
    },
    {
      "question":"What does the chemical symbol 'Y' represent?",
      "options":["A. Xylocaine","B. Ytterbium","C. Titanium","D. Yttrium"],
      "answer":"D. Yttrium"
    },
    {
      "question":"What does the chemical symbol 'Rh' represent?",
      "options":["A. Radium","B. Rhenium","C. Rayon","D. Rhodium"],
      "answer":"D. Rhodium" 
    },
    {
      "question":"What does the chemical symbol 'Ti' represent?",
      "options":["A. Thallium","B. Thorium","C. Titanium","D. Tellurium"],
      "answer":"C. Titanium"
    }
  ],

  // 7th Grade History

  [
    {
      "question":"Which country was an ally to the United States during the Revolutionary War?",
      "options":["A. Spain","B. Mexico","C. Canada","D. France"],
      "answer":"D. France"
    },
    {
      "question":"The 3/5th's Compromise dealt predominantly with whom?",
      "options":["A. Slaves","B. Southerners","C. Impoverished people","D. Northerners"],
      "answer":"A. Slaves"
    },
    {
      "question":"The First Amendment protects citizens' ____ and ____.",
      "options":["A. voting rights, rights to own weapons",
                  "B. freedom of speech, freedom of religion",
                  "C. home and private property",
                  "D. right to a lawyer and fair trial"],
      "answer":"B. freedom of speech, freedom of religion"
    },
    {
      "question":"In what year did American women win the right to vote?",
      "options":["A. 1930","B. 1923",
                  "C. 1920","D. 1922"],
      "answer":"C. 1920"
    },
    {
      "question":"Who was the first woman to run for President?",
      "options":["A. Sonia Johnson","B. Victoria Woodhull",
                  "C. Hillary Clinton","D. Belva Ann Lockwood"],
      "answer":"B. Victoria Woodhull"
    },
    {
      "question":"Which of these honors was Martin Luther King Jr. NOT awarded?",
      "options":[ "A. Nobel Peace Prize",
                  "B. Congressional Gold Medal",
                  "C. Presidential Medal of Freedom",
                  "D. Freedom Award"],
        "answer": "D. Freedom Award" 
    },
    // {
    //   "question":"Why did President Theodore Roosevelt establish the National Forest and Park Systems in the Early 20th century?",
    //   "options":[" A. To clear the timberlands for use as industrial areas",
    //               "B. To create more areas for the establishment of American Indian reservations",
    //               "C. To manage the use of resources and control industrial development in wilderness areas",
    //               "D. To stimulate development of a tourist industry to help bring revenue to the states"],
    //     "answer":"C. To manage the use of resources and control industrial development in wilderness areas"
    // },
    {
      "question":"Which of the following was NOT acquired by the U.S. at the end of the Spanish-American War?",
      "options":["A. Cuba","B. Puerto Rico",
                  "C. The Phillipines","D. Guam"],
      "answer":"A. Cuba"
    },
    {
      "question":"In what year did the Vietnam War begin?",
      "options":["A. 1970","B. 1955",
                  "C. 1950","D. 1972"],
      "answer":"B. 1955"
    }
    ]
  ],

  // 8th Grade Root Index
  [
   // 8th grade english
    [
      {
        "question":"The antonym of dirty is: ",
        "options":["A. Beautiful","B. Bad","C. Clean","D. Ugly"],
        "answer":"C. Clean"
      },
      {
        "question":"What does the word 'minutiae' mean?",
        "options":["A. artistic or aesthetic details","B. controversial or disputable details","C. unimportant or trifling details","D. negotiable details"],
        "answer":"C. unimportant or trifling details"
      },
      {
        "question":"What does the word 'chronological' mean?",
        "options":["A. arranged in the order events occured","B. arranged in a way that can be double-checked","C. arranged in the format required by law","D. arranged in no discernible pattern"],
        "answer":"A. arranged in the order events occured"
      },
      // {
      //   "question":"What type of sentence is this? 'Since it takes approximately 1000 years for a used printer cartridge to decompose, recycling these plastic ink dispensers helps the environment.'",
      //   "options":["A. simple","B. compound","C. complex","D. compound complex"],
      //   "answer":"C. complex"
      // },
      {
        "question":"What type of sentence is this? 'An avid reader, Ben attends weekly book club meetings, and he finishes several novels every month.'",
        "options":["A. simple","B. compound","C. complex","D. compound complex"],
        "answer":"B. compound"
      },
      {
        "question":"Complete the sentence: 'She _____ at me.'",
        "options":["A. smile","B. smiles","C. Is smiles","D. is smile"],
        "answer":"B. smiles"
      },
      {
        "question":"Complete the sentence: 'The person _____ you met this morning was my uncle.'",
        "options":["A. who","B. whom","C. that","D. which"],
        "answer":"B. whom"
      },
      {
        "question":"Which word is a synonym of 'deficient'?",
        "options":["A. lacking","B. dependent","C. judicious","D. affluent"],
        "answer":"A. lacking"
      },
      {
        "question":"The choir from Danville performed brilliantly during the final round of the match. 'Perform'is a(n):",
        "options":["A. adjective","B. adverb","C. clause","D. phrase"],
        "answer":"B. adverb"
      },
      {
        "question":"Put these words in alphabetical order: 'stake, sack, fowl, formal'",
        "options":["A. stake, sack, fowl, formal","B. fowl, formal, stake, sack","C. formal, fowl, sack, stack","D. formal, stake, sack, fowl"],
        "answer":"C. formal, fowl, sack, stack"
      },
    ],

    // 8th grade math
    [
      {
        "question":"Which numbers are factors of 10",
        "options":["A. 1 and 4","B. 1 and 2","C. 3 and 9","D. 2 and 6"],
        "answer":"B. 1 and 2"
      },
      // {
      //   "question":"After earning 700 points on a game show, Malia got to compete in the bonus round. During the bonus round, she lost 100 points on the gardening questions. What was her final score?",
      //   "options":["A. 800","B. -600","C. 600","D. -800"],
      //   "answer":"C. 600"
      // },
      {
        "question":"What is the percent of change from 24 to 36?",
        "options":["A. 50% decrease","B. 50% increase","C. 38% decrease","D. 38% increase"],
        "answer":"B. 50% increase"
      },
      {
        "question":"A triangle has angle measurements of 90°, 79°, and 11°. What kind of triangle is it?",
        "options":["A. acute","B. right","C. left","D. obtuse"],
        "answer":"B. right"
      },
      {
        "question":"What is 2/4 in its lowest terms?",
        "options":["A. 1/2","B. 1/3","C. 4/5","D. 3/6"],
        "answer":"A. 1/2"
      },
      {
        "question":"An isosceles triangle has how many equal sides?",
        "options":["A. 1","B. 2","C. 3","D. 4"],
        "answer":"B. 2"
      },
      {
        "question":"A triangle has angle measurements of 1°, 177°, and 2°. What kind of triangle is it?",
        "options":["A. acute","B. right","C. left","D. obtuse"],
        "answer":"D. obtuse"
      },
      {
        "question":"The radius of a circle is 3 feet. What is the circle's diameter?",
        "options":["A. 3 feet","B. 1.5 feet","C. 6 feet", "D. 12 feet"],
        "answer":"C. 6 feet"
      },
      {
        "question":"What is the percentage change from 200,000 to 20,000?",
        "options":["A. 90% decrease","B. 112% increase","C. 112% decrease","D. 90% increase"],
        "answer":"A. 90% decrease"
      },
      {
        "question":"According to his bank statement, Seth spent $2,000 on a piano. If Seth's bank account started out with a balance of $8,000, what is the the final balance?",
        "options":["A. $10,000","B. $7,000","C. $6,000","D. $5,000"],
        "answer":"C. $6,000"
      }
    ],

    // 8th grade science
    [
      {
        "question":"What is the second outer most layer of the earth?",
        "options":["A. crust","B. inner core","C. outer core", "D. mantle"],
        "answer":"D. mantle"
      },
      {
        "question":"What is the second step of the scientific method?",
        "options":["A. Identify the question","B. Test the hypothesis","C. Draw a conclusion", "D. Communicate the findings"],
        "answer":"B. Test the hypothesis"
      },
      {
        "question":"What is responsible for breaking down sugar in a cell?",
        "options":["A. Mitochondria","B. Nucleus","C. Golgi", "D. Lysosomes"],
        "answer":"A. Mitochondria"
      },
      {
        "question":"What do the chemical changes of melting glass and settling dust have in common?",
        "options":["A. Both are physical changes","B. Both are chemical changes","C. Both are caused by heating", "D. Both are caused by cooling"],
        "answer":"A. Both are physical changes"
      },
      {
        "question":"The earth gets most of its light from ?",
        "options":["A. the moon","B. the sun","C. stars", "D. other planets"],
        "answer":"B. the sun"
      },
      {
        "question":"In which part of a plant cell does photosynthesis occur?",
        "options":["A. Nucleus","B. Chloroplast","C. Cell Wall", "D. Cell Membrane"],
        "answer":"B. Chloroplast"
      },
      {
        "question":"Herbivores obtain most of their energy by...",
        "options":["A. Consuming animals","B. Consuming plants","C. absorbing sunlight", "D. producing sugar"],
        "answer":"B. Consuming plants"
      },
      {
        "question":"Approximately how long does it take for the Moon to complete one orbit around the Earth?",
        "options":["A. 1 month","B. 1 week","C. 1 year", "D. 1 day"],
        "answer":"A. 1 month"
      },
      {
        "question":"It is wise to wear sunglasses in Polar regions because of the bright, _____ light.",
        "options":["A. refracted","B. reflected","C. transmitted", "D. absorbed"],
        "answer":"B. reflected"
      },
      {
        "question":"When the environment changes and organisms do not adapt, a species could become _____.",
        "options":["A. regulated","B. classified","C. developed", "D. extinct"],
        "answer":"D. extinct"
      },
    ],

    // 8th grade history
    [
      {
        "question":"Who was the second president of the United States?",
        "options":["A. James Madison","B. James Monroe","C. John Adams", "D. John Quincy Adams"],
        "answer":"C. John Adams"
      },
      {
        "question":"How does the U.S. Constitution maintain a democratic government?",
        "options":["A. By specifying the role of the Supreme Court","B. By allowing the public to elect representatives","C. By limiting the terms of the US president", "D. By giving the president veto power"],
        "answer":"B. By allowing the public to elect representatives"
      },
      {
        "question":"Which of these 19th-century presidents was impeached?",
        "options":["A. Andrew Jackson","B. Andrew Johnson","C. John Tyler", "D. Zachary Taylor"],
        "answer":"B. Andrew Johnson"
      },
      {
        "question":"What was the purpose of the Mayflower Compact?",
        "options":["A. To establish freedom of religion","B. Serve as a set of rules for self-governance","C. To proclaim allegiance to the king", "D. To establish a new king"],
        "answer":"B. Serve as a set of rules for self-governance"
      },
      {
        "question":"Who was the U.S. fighting against in the War of 1812?",
        "options":["A. Great Britain", "B. Mexico", "C. France", "D. Italy"],
        "answer":"A. Great Britain"
      },
      {
        "question":"What product did prohibition outlaw in the early 1900s?",
        "options":["A. Alcohol","B. Slavery","C. Prohibiting women from voting", "D. Segregation"],
        "answer":"A. Alcohol"
      },
      {
        "question":"Who wrote the Declaration of Independence?",
        "options":["A. Benjamin Franklin","B. John Quincy Adams","C. George Washington", "D. Thomas Jefferson"],
        "answer":"D. Thomas Jefferson"
      },
      {
        "question":"Who won World War II?",
        "options":["A. Axis powers","B. America and England","C. America", "D. The Allied Powers"],
        "answer":"D. The Allied Powers"
      },
      {
        "question":"What was the name of the document written by Abraham Lincoln that helped free slaves in the Confederate states?",
        "options":["A. The Slavery Decree","B. The Eleventh Amendment","C. The Freedman Order", "D. The Emancipation Proclamation"],
        "answer":"D. The Emancipation Proclamation"
      },
      {
        "question":"What American aided wounded soldiers on the battlefield during the Civil War?",
        "options":["A. Martha Simpson","B. Betsy Ross","C. Clara Barton", "D. Dolly Madison"],
        "answer":"C. Clara Barton"
      },
    ]
  ]
]

module.exports =questions;